There was a large package
当时有一个大型的快递
that fell from above.
从上面掉下来
Do you remember that?
你还记得吗
I often watched you play
那边篮球场
at the basketball court.
我经常看你打球
You remember that, right?
你总记得吧
I honestly didn't notice.
我还真没注意过
How could that be?
怎么可能啊
Back then,
当时
your roommate Chen
你室友晨哥
was dating my bestie Liu Liu.
跟我闺蜜刘柳在谈恋爱
I was always around
你们打球的时候
when you played.
我都在呀
And we often
而且咱们几个
had dinners together.
经常一起聚餐
I do have a bit of an impression.
有一点点印象
But
不过
it seems we didn't
当时我们好像
talk much back then.
没怎么说过话
Yuhui,
小唐
that was in the past.
以前是以前
Now we are
现在我们是
colleagues.
上下级的关系
I hope that in the future,
我还是希望以后
no matter the occasion,
无论在任何场合下
don't be ambiguous.
我们不要言语模糊地
Don't mislead others
去引导别人
into misunderstanding our relationship.
误会我们的关系
I know you're worried that others
我知道你是怕别人
might gossip about me behind my back.
知道之后在背后非议我
It's fine.
没关系
I don't mind that.
我不在乎这些
By the way,
对了
there's a class reunion tonight.
晚上同学聚会
I've already called the guys.
我约好了
Will you go?
一起去吗
I've got other plans,
我还有事
so I won't be going.
就不去了
See you on Monday.
周一行里见
Xiaoning.
筱柠
They're just so-so.
也不过如此啊
Back in my day,
我当年啊
I was the top small forward on campus.
可是校内的第一小前锋
In terms of strength, speed, and skills,
论力量速度还有技巧
I could easily outshine all the boys.
秒杀所有男生
If you had seen
你要是见到
my glory back then,
当年我的风采
you would have been charmed by me.
肯定会被我迷上的
Who brags like that?
哪有你这么自卖自夸的
Mr. Ji, you're quite the narcissist.
纪先生你好自恋啊
Thank you.
谢谢啊
You weren't the type to
你上大学的时候
just barely make it to class,
应该不是那种
were you?
踩着点上课的学生吧
Of course not.
当然不是了
I practically lived in the classroom.
我都住在教室里了
Really?
真的假的
Of course not.
当然是假的
You're so annoying.
讨厌
Back in college,
大学的时候呀
I came to this library every day.
每天都会来这个图书馆
This path,
这条路
if you go that way,
往那边走
leads back to the dorm.
就是回宿舍的路
On this floor,
就这个地板上
I know exactly where it's worn out.
哪个地方有坏的
The bushes by the road,
这路边的灌木丛
I know which season
什么季节能够开花
they bloom.
我都一清二楚的
Back then, every day,
当时其实每天
as I walked by, I thought,
在走的时候就在想
if only I had someone
要是能有一个人
to accompany me.
陪着我就好了
I'll be with you.
我陪着你啊
I want to take you
我呢现在想带你
to explore every path.
走完这每一条路
I hope that when I look back
就是希望以后再想起来
on my college days,
大学的时光的时候
I won't feel lonely.
就不孤单了
At that time,
你上大学的时候
did you really just focus on studies
真的只知道学习
and not date at all?
没有谈恋爱吗
Of course not.
当然没有了
That's 'cause you're holding onto
那是因为心里
that dream girl in your heart.
装着那个白月光吧
She's quite something.
白月光威力还真大
You don't believe me?
不相信我
No.
没有
Definitely not.
没有 没有
This is my dormitory.
这个就是我的宿舍
It's a long time.
只是没想到
These balconies
这么多年过去了
are
这阳台
unexpectedly sealed off.
还给封起来
What's up?
怎么了
What's your history
你跟这阳台
with that?
还有什么爱恨情仇啊
You know,
你不知道
our room
我们宿舍
is the farthest from the library.
离图书馆是最远的
Every time the library closed,
每次图书馆闭馆了
the dorm also had to close.
宿舍楼也准关门了
So I had to
所以我只能
climb in through the balcony.
从这阳台上翻进去了
You really worked hard, huh?
这么用功啊
That's like going through four more
你这等于
senior years of high school.
又上了四年高三
That's ridiculous.
离谱
When we have kids in the future,
等以后咱们生了孩子
you'll understand
你就能知道
how important it is to have
有一个爱读书的老公
a husband who loves to study.
有多重要了
Who's going to have kids with you?
谁要跟你生孩子呀
Wait.
不对
Who said I'd marry you?
谁答应跟你结婚了
Alright then.
行
So,
那
we won't have kids.
就不生孩子
That way, no one will interrupt
这样就没人打扰
our little world.
我们的二人世界
When we get older,
等咱们老了
we can go
就去
to a nursing home.
养老院去
C'mon, kids one moment
你一会儿生孩子
and a nursing home the next.
一会儿养老院的
Are you thinking
你是不是想得有点
too far ahead?
太远了
That's because
那是因为
in my plan for life,
在我的人生计划里
you've always been a part of it.
一直都有你
Aren't you embarrassed?
你害不害臊
You're so
不害臊
full of yourself.
脸皮真厚
Ji Yuheng?
纪昱恒
Sun Chen!
孙晨
Yuheng!
昱恒
How fancy!
真的是你啊
What are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿
Don't you remember?
昱恒你忘啦
After I finished graduate school,
我研究生毕业
I stayed on as an instructor.
留校当老师呢
I really forgot about that.
我还真忘了
Who is this?
这位是
I'm his girlfriend,
我是他女朋友
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
Nice meeting you.
你好
Look at him.
你看他
I think
我觉得
he's getting cuter lately.
他最近越来越帅了
Yeah.
对
Honestly, right now,
要我说现在就是
Ji Yuheng
纪昱恒啊
is really a busy guy.
真的是大忙人
So hard to get a hold of him.
太难约了
He didn't even show up for gatherings.
聚会也不来
He really does
他现在确实
have work to handle,
还有工作要忙
so he asked me
就过来让我
to say hi to everyone
跟大家打个招呼
and apologize.
道个歉
Yuhui is still looking out for him, huh?
羽卉还护着他呢
Tell us the truth,
你说实话
you two aren't just
你们俩不是单纯的
colleagues, are you?
同事关系吧
You're out of the loop.
你都落伍啦
They had something
他俩在大学的时候啊
special
关系啊
back in college.
就不一般啦
Really?
有吗
I don't think so.
我觉得没有吧
Just that one time
就那次
in front of the first building,
在一教前面
he saved her,
英雄救美
remember?
你不记得啦
Hey!
同学
Hold on a second.
等一下
Actually, that's pretty straightforward.
其实那个挺简单的
Watch out!
小心
Are you alright?
没事吧
Here you go.
给
Thanks.
谢谢
Did you
你刚刚
need me for something?
叫我有什么事吗
It's nothing.
没什么
Wrong person.
认错人了
Let's go.
走吧
Go.
走
Are you alright?
没事吧
So scary!
吓死我了
I'm fine.
没事
What was that?
怎么回事这
Oh my!
天哪
A hero saving a damsel!
英雄救美
Such a classic move for flirting.
就是这撩妹的手段
Isn't it a bit cliché?
也太老套了点吧
Flirting?
撩妹
Exactly!
对啊
So obvious.
多明显
Pretending to mistake someone,
故意说是认错了
but really,
其实啊
he just wants you to remember him.
就是想让你记住他呢
Is that guy
那个人是不是
Sun Chen's roommate?
孙晨的室友啊
He's actually
长得
pretty hot.
还蛮帅的啊
Be honest with me,
你老实说
did he save you 'cause he likes you,
他是因为喜欢你才救你
or did he fall for you
还是救了你之后
after saving you?
对你一见钟情呢
Does it really matter?
有差别吗
Anyway, the first time he
反正他第一眼
looked at Yuhui,
看向羽卉的眼神
his eyes were filled with love.
浓烈的爱意呀
It was intense!
波涛汹涌啊
Aren't you guys
那现在岂不是
super close nowadays?
近水楼台
Ji Yuheng
纪昱恒
has a better chance to win over you.
更容易得到月啦
I've only been working for Dairui
我才来代瑞
for one year.
一年
Right now,
我们现在
we're still focused on work.
还是以工作为主
I see what you mean.
我懂了啊
I got it.
我听懂了
Let's give President Ji
给纪行长
some time.
一些时间
After all, he's a man.
男人嘛
He needs to be
还是要
put to the test.
考验 考验
In that case,
那我就
I'll be waiting for your wedding!
等你们的喜酒啦
We haven't got that far yet.
我还早着呢
I'm looking forward to yours.
等着喝你们的
We haven't got there either.
我们也早着呢
Sorry for being late.
不好意思啊各位
- Hi, there. - You're late, man.
来晚了 你怎么才来呀
I ran into an old friend on the way
我这路上碰到个老熟人
and chatted for a bit.
跟他聊了一会儿
Guess who
你们猜
I bumped into?
我碰到谁啦
Who was it?
谁呀
You'll never guess.
绝对猜不到啊
It was Yuheng,
老纪
Ji Yuheng!
纪昱恒
My roommate!
就我那室友
Remember him?
想起来没
I'm telling you,
我跟你们说
he's showing
我看到纪昱恒啊
his girlfriend
正带他女朋友
around campus.
逛学校呢
Really!
真的
That guy...
那个小子
He's really something, you know.
老行了我跟你说
Are you just
你 你是不是
making this up?
瞎猜的
Yeah.
对呀
He couldn't possibly
不能有
have a girlfriend, right?
女朋友吧
That's his girl for sure!
如假包换
He introduced her to me himself.
他自己给我介绍的
And that girl
而且人家那女孩
actually
亲口承认说
admitted that.
就是他女朋友
You've got know,
我跟你们说
the way he looks at his girlfriend
纪昱恒看女朋友那眼神
is incredibly gentle.
那叫一个温柔的
At first, I thought
其实一开始我以为
Yuheng would be into those
昱恒应该是喜欢那种
gorgeous types.
明艳挂的大美女
I didn't expect someone to be so pure.
没想到找了个清新挂的
Well.
你说这
He told me
他自己跟我说
to keep it a secret from you all.
要跟你们保密的
But then,
结果
he got caught.
被撞见了
So you knew all along?
原来你是知道啊
She knew it.
早知道 早知道
What a blunder!
乌龙 乌龙
I thought
我还以为
I discovered some big secret.
发现个啥秘密呢
Sun Chen,
孙晨
you're late.
你迟到了啊
You owe three drinks!
自罚三杯
Pour it up, pour it up!
倒上 倒上 倒上
Three drinks, OK?
三杯啊
Come on, come on!
来 来 来
Alright, alright!
好 好 好
Today, I'll
我孙晨今天
give it my best!
舍命陪君子啦
Just a little less.
少倒点 少倒点
Fill it up!
满上 满上
I have class tomorrow.
我这明天还有课
I'll
我就
drink as a toast!
先干为敬啦
Sorry.
不好意思
Watch your head.
小心头啊
Careful.
小心啊
Come on.
来
Back in college,
其实大学的时候
my only way to unwind
我唯一的消遣方式
was to come here and read.
就是来这儿看书
Whenever I had a free moment,
找个没课的时候
I would quietly sit
一个人安静地
in that corner by myself.
坐在那个角落
I could easily spend the whole day there.
一看就能看上一天
Wow, Yuheng!
真是小纪同学啊
I thought I was mistaken.
我还以为我看错了呢
Sir, you still remember me?
老板您还记得我
How could I forget you?
怎么会忘了呢
You used to come here
你上大学的时候
when you were in college.
隔三岔五就来
Such a handsome young man,
这么一帅小伙儿
always sitting alone in the corner,
总是一个人坐在角落里
reading philosophy books.
看哲学读本
You seemed low-key,
看似低调
but you actually stood out a lot.
实则招眼得很啊
You've never brought anyone here before.
这还是第一次带人来呀
Your girlfriend?
女朋友
Sir,
老板
he really hasn't brought
他真的没带过
any other girls here?
别的女生来过啊
Yeah.
是啊
I even asked him
我还问他呢
why he didn't bring his girlfriend.
怎么不带女朋友来
He said he
他说呀
has someone he likes.
他有喜欢的人啦
I asked him
我问他
what she looks like.
喜欢的人什么样
He said...
他说
I forgot the exact words,
原话我忘记了
but...
好像
Just like you.
就是姑娘你这样
Like me?
我这样
The only impression I have is
唯一有印象的就是
that when she smiles,
眼睛一笑起来
her eyes curve into a line.
弯成一条线
They're incredibly bright.
特别爽朗
Just looking at her lifts his spirits.
看着就心情好啥的
Come on, don't make fun of me.
您就别开我玩笑了
You're blushing!
还害羞了
Alright then.
行
You guys help yourself.
那你们随便逛
OK.
好
Thanks.
那您先忙
The girl he mentioned
老板说那姑娘
is your dream girl, right?
就是你的白月光吧
Yes.
是
But honestly...
但其实
I don't want to know who she is.
我不想知道她是谁啊
Whatever,
不管她是谁
the important thing is,
反正现在
we're together now.
咱们两个在一起了
Even if she's here,
就算她回来了
I won't let her have you.
我也不会让给她的
You two should just give up on that idea.
你们俩死了这条心吧
You're quite lucky, huh?
你小子还挺走运的
You missed one dream girl,
错过一个白月光
but you found a similar one.
还能遇到一个同款的
OK, back online.
亮了
Nothing serious.
没啥大事
Just a loose air switch
就是空气开关松了
causing intermittent tripping.
导致间歇性跳闸
I'm going to wash up.
我去洗洗啊
The restroom is over here.
洗手间在这边
I've got grease all over my hands.
我一手的润滑油
I need detergent.
不得拿洗洁精搓搓
It's that simple, huh?
这么简单
What's wrong with
你这厨房下水管道
your kitchen drain?
又怎么了
Oh.
那个啊
It doesn't need fixing.
那个不用修
I don't use the
我这厨房
kitchen much anyway.
平时也不怎么用
Unlike that,
不像那个
the electrical box needs repair for sure.
电箱非修不可
Since I'm here,
我都来了就一起
I might as well help you with it.
给你弄了吧
Really, it's not necessary.
真的没必要
The lease is ending,
这房子到期了
and I won't be renting anymore.
我也不租了
You know, let's say
你说你这个人吧
you don't care about the quality of life,
说你不讲究生活品质
yet you carry designer bags
背名牌包
and wear designer shoes.
穿名牌鞋
You get manicures every week.
美甲护理周周不落
So why is your life
怎么这日子
so chaotic?
就过得这么糟心呢
You don't do your laundries,
衣服不洗
or take out your trash.
垃圾不收
And your water pipe
这水管
is still dripping.
还滴滴答答地
Anyway, since you've got nothing to do,
反正现在没什么事
you should cook something at home.
你就在家里面做点吃的
Since you know how to cook,
又不是不会做饭
give up those
别整天吃外面的
pre-packaged meals.
预制菜料理包
They aren't good for your health.
那样对身体不好
If you're
你要
really too lazy to cook,
实在是懒得做
just ask those young
去找那什么
booty calls
小屁孩
to do for you.
让他给你做
You know,
你也知道
those are just kids.
那些都是小屁孩
They're still
他们也都还是
their parents' little darlings.
爸妈的心肝宝贝呢
How could they
怎么可能
cook for me?
为我洗手做汤羹
Frankly,
说白了吧
those younger guys
那些弟弟们
are just
对于我就是
infatuated with mature women.
对于成熟女性的迷恋
Besides, I live my life
再加上我这个人
with such style,
活得又潇洒
and I'm quite generous.
出手也阔绰
And I'm not
长得吧
bad-looking either, right?
也没这么差是不是
So everyone
所以大家呢
is just playing along.
就只是逢场作戏
It's an unspoken agreement.
心照不宣罢了
Why force someone
干吗强迫人家
to settle down with me?
非要跟我过什么日子
Alright,
好了
this hose is broken.
你这个软管坏了
I'll just tape it up for now.
我先拿胶带给你缠上
Later,
回头啊
I'll get you a new one.
我给你买一根新的
Honestly,
我觉得
you're quite
你倒是
suitable for settling down.
挺适合过日子的啊
So what?
有什么用呢
After all these years,
这么多年
I'm still on my own.
还不是我一个人
I'm on my own as well.
我不也是一个人吗
Do you know
我跟你讲
tough it was
你知道吗
when I first started living alone?
我刚独居的时候有多惨
One time,
有一次啊
my appliances broke down.
我家的家电坏了
I had to call the landlord for help.
然后呢找房东帮我修
Guess what?
你猜怎么着
He scammed me out of half a month's rent.
他骗了我半个月的房租
There was another time,
还有一次
someone broke into my house.
我家进小偷了
At that moment,
然后那个时候
I was terrified.
我吓坏了
So I just lay in bed,
我就躺在床上
didn't dare to move.
一动不敢动
I could hear him
然后我就听他在那儿
rummaging through my things.
翻箱倒柜的
In the end, I have no idea
最后他偷了什么走
what he took.
我也不知道
Honestly, I didn't have
反正我们家
anything valuable at home.
没什么值钱东西
Another time,
还有一次
I went to the kitchen
就是在厨房
to get something.
我进厨房来拿东西
But the door was broken.
谁知道厨房那个门坏了
I couldn't get out.
然后我就出不去了
My phone was left in the living room.
手机呢又扔在客厅
Guess what happened next?
你猜最后怎么着
I had to use
我就是拿那个
the kitchen knife
切菜的菜刀
to break the lock
把厨房那个门的锁
on the door.
给劈了
That's how I finally got out.
我才出去的
You don't need to look.
你不用看
It's not this place.
不是这套房子
I didn't have much money back then,
我那时候没什么钱
and that place I rented
那房子租的都已经
was almost on the outskirts.
快要出星城了
That's not right.
不对呀
With your personality,
以你饶姐姐的性格
you should just
不应该是
argue with the landlord about rent,
在房租上跟房东硬刚
corner the thief
然后把小偷
and
堵在墙角
call the police,
报警
just
不开心
chop the
你就直接
door
把整个门给
into pieces
劈了
completely.
给锁陪葬
I already told you,
我都跟你说了
that was when I first lived alone.
那是我刚独居的时候
I just started back then.
好吗刚独居
Besides,
再说了
who is born strong and invulnerable?
谁天生强势百毒不侵
Haven't I managed on my own
我不也是这么多年
all these years?
自己过过来
So that's how I became who I'm today.
才变成现在这样吗
Why are you telling me all this?
你干吗跟我说这些
Nothing, just...
没干吗
You were just
你刚才在那儿
nagging with me, right?
不是跟我唠叨吗
So I'll just
那我也就
nag a bit back at you.
跟你唠叨两句呗
While you were
就是你刚才
going on about that,
在唠叨那个过程当中
I was thinking,
我在想
over the years, I've spent so much time
这些年我大把的时间
either working
不是用在工作上
or just fooling around.
就是用在游戏人生了
So I wonder if my life
那我想我的生活
could have another possibility.
会不会有另外一种可能
What if I had
有一个
a trustworthy,
值得信任
mutually supportive partner?
相互依靠的伴侣
Coming home to a light,
回家有盏灯
with warm meals waiting for me.
永远有热的饭菜在等你
Wouldn't that be nice?
是不是也挺好
Wait a minute.
等会儿
What exactly are we doing?
说清楚到底什么意思
I'm ready to get serious about dating.
我准备认真谈一场恋爱
But whether we'll have a future
但是我们会不会有结果
depends on how you manage it.
还要看你表现
I promise I won't disappoint you.
不会让你失望的
Weiyi!
惟依
What brings you here?
你怎么来啦
I came to welcome you back.
接你下班啊
How does it feel
正式上班
to officially start your job?
感觉怎么样呀
It's quite fun.
挺有意思的
Did you notice that
你来的路上看见那个
duck neck shop on your way?
鸭脖店了吗
Where is it?
在哪儿
Just turn right on your way out.
就出门右拐那家
It's an old brand that often has long lines.
百年老字号天天排长队
Next to it,
旁边呢
a new nail salon just opened.
新开了一家美甲店
It's a new one.
新开的
It's very popular among girls.
很招女孩喜欢
The owners of these two stores
这两家老板呀
are always arguing
天天为这门口
over trifles.
一亩三分地
They argue every day.
天天吵
It's quite a scene.
吵得不可开交
Today, it got so bad that we had to respond.
今天都吵到我们出警了
Really?
真假的
Hey, check this out.
还有这个
That serious, huh?
那么严重
Let me see.
我看
A puppy?
小狗
Your
这
cases include catching dogs?
这追狗也是你们的案子
Of course!
可不
The people
人民群众
encounter all sorts of problems in life
在生活里遇到各种问题
and will come to us for help.
都会找我们
From
小到
illegal renovations and neighbor disputes
违规装修邻居吵架
to business owners being
大到企业老板
threatened with acid attacks by shareholders.
被股民威胁泼硫酸
These are valuable experience.
我这回长见识了
It's quite impressive, actually.
还挺有模有样的啊
Your line of work
看你们这工作
seems pretty exhausting.
还挺饱和的吗
Then you really need to stay fit
那你更要强身健体
and improve your health.
增强增强体质
How about
这样
we do some sports this weekend?
周末我们一块去运动呗
Sounds good!
可以啊
What sport?
什么运动
I have a friend
我有个朋友呢
who just opened a windsurfing club
新开了一个帆板俱乐部
right in the sea area.
就在星城的海域
It's really fun!
特别好玩
You should come with me.
到时候你陪我一块去啊
For activities like this,
参加这种活动
don't you have to pay in advance?
是不是得提前交费啊
How much is it? Let me give you the money.
多少钱我转给你
It's not much.
没多少钱
I've got it covered.
我到时一起付了就行
Did you forget again?
是不是又忘了
We agreed that I won't spend your money.
说好了不花你的钱的
How much is it?
多少钱
For this club,
这个帆板俱乐部吧
you need to hire an instructor,
它是要请私教
the one-on-one kind.
一对一的那种
6,000 yuan.
六千块
I know.
我知道
You don't want to spend my dad's money.
你不想花我爸的钱
You can take it
那这次就当
as if I lent it to you.
我先借给你
When you get paid,
等你发工资了
you can invite me for something else,
你再请我玩别的
OK?
好不好吗
Weiyi,
惟依
this isn't about borrowing and repaying,
这不是借钱还钱的问题
but the economic gap between us.
是咱们两个经济差距
It may affect our spending habits.
带来消费观的问题
We're both pushing thirty.
咱们俩都快三十了
We can't just keep playing around.
总不能一直玩吧
Shouldn't we think about the future?
是不是得想想以后
I still want to
我还是想把
save up the money I have.
省下的钱攒一攒
When the time comes for us to buy a house,
等到时候咱俩想买房
and pay the mortgage,
还贷款
the pressure might be a bit less.
压力是不是可以小一点
Why do you keep bringing up
你为什么又扯上
the future and houses?
未来啊房子啊这些
Are we supposed to sacrifice
我们难道因为未来
our current happiness
房子这些要牺牲掉
for the future?
现在的快乐吗
I have money,
我有钱
so why should I
为什么要斤斤计较
be stingy?
想着怎么去花钱呀
That's no fun
这多没意思呀
at all!
生活过的
I just want you
我就想让你
to join me for some windsurfing.
陪我去玩个帆板而已
But you're
你倒好
making it all about
在这儿什么上纲上线
economics and spending habits.
扯什么经济能力消费观
If you don't want to go, just say so.
你要不想玩你可以直说
I didn't mean it.
我没有说不想玩
I don't have to do it with you.
我没有非要你陪
I can go by myself.
我自己也可以去
Weiyi!
惟依
Thanks.
谢谢
Coming tomorrow?
你明天还来吗
Sure, if I'm free.
没事就来呗
I think it's
我感觉这运动
quite fun.
还挺好玩的
Yeah?
是吧
Wanna split
那你要不要
the gear with me?
跟我拼下装备
It's a sweet deal,
它是一个大礼包
like a starter pack with
它里面有一个帆面
a sail, 3 masts,
三节细桅杆
and halyard.
帆杆起帆绳
Like everything
反正啊
a beginner needs.
新手需要的装备
If we buy together,
它全都有
we get 20% off.
两个人成团打八折
Only 4,800 yuan.
只要四千八
We're edging towards 30,
咱们俩都快三十了
gotta think beyond
总不能一直玩吧
just having fun, huh?
是不是得想想以后
I'm gonna stash
我还是想把
away what I can,
省下的钱攒一攒
so when we wanna
等到时候咱俩想买房
buy a house,
还贷款
we'll have less to worry.
压力是不是可以小一点
I'm good.
先不买了
I wanna make sure
等我确定
I really like the sports before I buy.
我自己真的喜欢我再买
Fine.
好吧
I'll ask around then.
那我再问问别人
Bye.
拜拜
It's been a whole day.
都一整天了
He hasn't even sent me a message.
连个消息都没有
He can't be serious about
总不至于真的要因为
splitting up
钱这点破事
over money, can he?
跟我分手吧
It's crazy
也不知道
how such
从什么时候开始
trifles are
越来越多这些小事
eating into our relationship.
会影响到我们的感情
Alright, Qi Yu.
行齐郁
Since you don't come to me,
既然你不来找我
I'll come to you.
那我就去找你
We said we'd grind
说好一块开黑的
together and split the cash
装备打下来卖了钱平分
from selling gear.
大家平分
But now,
你说
what's the deal?
现在怎么成这样了
Don't touch him.
别动手啊
Come over here.
你俩先过来待会儿来
Clarify your demands,
搞清楚各自诉求
got it?
明白吗
I gotta lend it, right?
我不能不借吧
Hey, you didn't even ask!
那你跟我说吗
Calm down.
冷静一下啊
If you did, I wouldn't
你要跟我说我会不借吗
have said no, would I?
那钱是不是
That money's
也有我的一部分
partly mine too, isn't it?
是不是也有我的一部分
You're really making
我发现你现在
no sense right now.
很不可理喻
What's going on?
什么情况
What the hell?
我哪里不可理喻了
You're ridiculous!
你就是不可理喻
Why do I gotta
那我为啥
report to you for everything?
这个都要跟你说
It's our money!
那是我们共同的钱哪
Just ask and I'd lend,
那你跟我说下
wouldn't I?
我会不借吗
Kiddo, let's go have some fun.
叔叔跟你出去玩一会儿
Okay?
好不好
Do you even respect me?
你尊重我没有
Calm down.
冷静点 冷静点
Talk calmly.
好好说
This money ain't nothing!
这点钱不重要吗
You can't just
你说借就借
take it without asking me.
那是不是跟我说一下
But I didn't have time!
那我不是来不及吗
Sir.
警察同志
Will you
我儿子摸黑
do something about my son
把我存折偷走这个事啊
stealing my bankbook?
你们到底管不管
Yes.
管 管 管
We will.
肯定管
Write down your request.
把要求写一下
Okay.
好 好 好
Sir,  should I lend it?
警察同志你说我该借吗
Haven't eaten a thing?
一天没吃饭
Too busy to
今天没抽出空
eat today.
太忙了
I had day shift today,
本来我今天是白班的
wanting to get you after,
然后想着下班去接你
but my buddy's
结果换班的时候
mom got a stroke,
我那同事妈妈
and was hospitalized,
突然脑梗住院了
so I stayed for him.
我就留下替他
Not mad at me, are you?
你没生气吧
No.
没事
I didn't realize your job
我不知道原来你这工作
was so demanding.
这么辛苦
You caught
你今天碰上了
the busiest time today.
赶上人最多的时候
It's not usually this busy.
平时人没这么多
Earning money is tough.
赚钱真不容易啊
Of course.
赚钱嘛
It's quite tough.
肯定不容易
But helping people
不过为人民服务吧
feels good.
还挺有成就感的
Keeps me grounded,
忙是忙点
knowing I'm doing
不过心里特踏实
something real.
感觉干事了
Good then.
那就好
Thanks to my job, paycheck
我虽然也是拿工资
comes in.
有工作
But
但是
I never thought about just
我从来没有想过
surviving on that small amount.
靠那三千块钱而活
I spend
每次都是
what I got,
有多少钱花多少
and it's all good.
也觉得好像没什么问题
Sorry.
对不起啊
I was
我之前
always judging
总是按照
you by my own rules,
我的标准去要求你
didn't think about how you felt.
却没有考虑过你的感受
Weiyi.
惟依
Forget it.
你别这么讲
I...
其实我
I tried sailboarding
我今天去玩帆板了
and I found
我玩了一圈之后
that it
发现好像
wasn't my jam.
那玩意儿也没什么意思
The shoes
之前的皮鞋
and the sailboard,
还有这次的帆板
I kinda
其实都是我
forced them
自作主张
on you.
强加给你的
I was wrong
我想了一下这事
about that.
确实是我不对
Let's talk things through
以后要是有什么事
from now on, cool?
咱俩商量着来呗
Cool.
行
Qi Yu.
小齐
Just a minute,
等我一下啊
I'll be right back.
马上回来
Coming.
来了
Since Prof. Jia's on board
其实贾教授答应
as a financial expert,
作为财务专家加入之后
Mr. Xia's
夏总
totally into it now.
明显变得更有兴趣了
We're meeting again
我们已经约好
in five days to chat more.
五天之后再去面谈
Great.
太好了
You said
你昨晚说
his attitude flipped.
夏总态度有所转变
Big bosses are all ears.
总行领导高度重视
They promised that
要我传话给你
all relevant depts
说行里呢
would cooperate with you
会安排所有相关部门
to make connections
鼎力配合这次对接
and implement the best plan.
协助最优方案落地
Quoting words from higher-ups,
领导的原话是这样
"Grab the chance,"
牢抓机遇
"give it your all."
全力以赴
Clear?
懂吗
Yes.
明白
Don't worry, sir,
老师您也放心
I'm gonna give it my all
我一定会尽最大的努力
to make this partnership work.
促成这次合作
We said to take it easy,
说好的一起松松绑的
but he's
他是真的
pulling out all the stops!
一点武德都不讲
He
还
even dragged
还把那什么
his mentor
自己的导师
into the mix?
给整过来了
What's his game?
干吗呢这是啊
Showing off
在我面前炫耀
that fancy school he went to?
他上的学校比我好
Huh?
是不是啊
Chill out, boss.
邢总别生气
It's early days yet.
这才哪儿到哪儿啊
Who knows
最后什么结果
what'll happen?
还不一定呢
I've been kicking myself
我这两天一直在想
for dropping
这提前放弃
the Weiji project
惟纪公司这个项目
too soon.
是不是有点太仓促了
Yeah.
是啊
If we'd found
如果当初咱们
a way in, our S2
也找一个切入点的话
would be killing it
那现在的风光
right now.
就都是咱们二部的了
Hello? Zhang?
喂 老张
Juicy gossip?
小道消息
I'm all ears.
那我肯定要听一听了
Really?
真的假的
I told you.
我就说嘛
I'm not
我老邢绝不是
a quitter.
轻言放弃的人
When I say no,
我说不行的事情
it's a dead end,
天王老子来了
no matter who's pulling strings.
也折腾不出什么花来
Okay.
行
Thank you so much.
谢谢啊老张
Dinner's on me next time.
回头请你吃饭
Yeah.
好嘞
Mr Xing.
邢总
Good news?
什么好消息
Spill the beans.
跟我们分享分享呗
You nailed it.
还真被你给说准了
Weiji's leader
惟纪公司
of its overseas business unit
海外事业部的负责人
is dipping.
要辞职
Xia Mingrui
这夏明睿啊
has to fly out there
要紧急过去处理
the day after tomorrow.
后天就走
He's got
这两天
no gaps
他的行程
in his calendar
安排得是满满的
for Ji Yuheng
根本就没有时间
at all.
见那纪昱恒那小子
Looks like
这么看来
his
纪昱恒
big meeting is gonna
那心心念念的会面
be a no-show.
怕是要泡汤喽
Xia Mingrui
那个夏明睿
spends over half the year
一年大半的时间
abroad.
都在国外
Who knows
这一去
how long
还真不知道
he'll be away this time.
他要待到什么时候
If
你说
he's gone
他要是这一待
for months,
待两三个月
that funding
那融资这事
could go up in smoke.
可能就会黄啊
Yeah.
是啊
We know in sales,
咱们干销售这么多年
delays
最忌讳一个词
equal disaster.
就是迟则生变
Mr Ji barely managed to get him on board.
领导好不容易才约到他
He's probably
现在说不定心里边
freaking out.
已经急成什么样了
Where to?
干吗去
Walk.
出去走走
I'll go with you.
一块去呗
Wait up.
等我一会儿
Xiaoning.
筱柠
What good will it do,
你觉得你现在进去
just walking in like that?
能帮到他什么
I saw you two on the street
前两天在路上的时候
a couple days ago.
我看到你们两个
And I know you followed
而且去京海出差的时候
him to Jinghai.
你跟过去了吧
You're crushing on him.
我知道你对他有意思
When he's
他现在
upset over his mom,
只是因为阿姨去世伤心
you're just taking advantage.
被你趁虚而入了
Don't be so naive,
你该不会真的
thinking he'll
天真地以为
really like you back.
他会喜欢上你吧
I'd ditch
我可以为了
Dairui Bank for him.
和他在一起离开代瑞
Would you?
你敢吗
Okay.
行
I'll call you back.
稍后我再回给你
Knock before you come in.
请记得进门之前先敲门
Yuheng.
师哥
What's up?
有什么事吗
I got a way in
惟纪的事情
with Weiji.
我可以帮得上忙
Yesterday I found out
我也是昨天才知道的
my dad's
我爸最近跟惟纪
got ties.
搭上了关系
I can hook you up.
我可以让你见到他
The company my dad
我爸投资的公司
has invested in
最近在帮惟纪
is helping Weiji's branch
在星城的子公司
with IPO.
做上市
Mr Xia will hang with them
夏明睿去美国之前
before he jets off to the US.
都会跟他们在一起
What do you want in return?
条件是什么
You'll say yes
我提什么条件
to anything?
你都会答应吗
I'll give it a good think
职权范围里的
if it's in my hands.
我一定会认真考量
If not, I'll take it
我无权应允你的
up the chain.
可以上报给行里
Not work-related.
跟工作无关
Yuheng.
师哥
I know you were
我知道前段时间
really down after
因为阿姨的事情
your mom passed away,
你状态很差
and Tu Xiaoning
需要人关心
just happened
需要人陪
to be there for you.
这才让涂筱柠钻了空子
I get it, totally.
这我都可以理解
But it's
可现在事情
been a while.
已经过去那么久了
You gotta
你难道还要纠缠
let that go
在这种没有意义的
and move on?
关系里面吗
She can't help you.
她帮不上你任何忙
And if words got
而且你们的关系
around the bank,
如果闹到行里
it could really
只会成为丑闻
mess up your career.
影响你的前途
Break it off with her.
离开涂筱柠
All I want is this.
我就这一个条件
If okay,
如果你可以做到
I promise to have you meet Mr Xia.
我保证让你见到夏明睿
And I'll help you with
而且你需要的
any other
其他人脉关系
connections you need.
我也都会想办法
I'll take care of
惟纪公司的事情
Weiji myself.
我会自己来解决
Appreciate the offer.
我谢谢你的好意
Yuheng.
师哥
You're sharp.
你是聪明人
This new
现在正是应聘
bank prez bid is huge.
新行长的关键时期
Fail now,
如果这次失败了
might wait
之后不知道
years.
还要等多少年
Don't regret it.
你别后悔
Tang Yuhui, seriously,
唐羽卉我最后再说一次
last time about
这是我最后一次容忍你
my personal stuff
在工作场合下
at work.
谈论我的私人问题
You know better than
公私不分是职场的大忌
to blur those lines.
我相信你很清楚
Get out.
出去
Nobody thinks they'll
不会真的有人以为
get away with
在办公室搞这种
office hookups
偷偷摸摸
without consequences,
不正当的男女关系
right?
会有什么好结果吧
Who are you referring to?
说谁呢这是
She knows it.
说谁谁知道
Think about it.
自己好好想想吧
Can you handle
如果出了问题
the fallout if things go south?
到底能不能承担得了
She knows?
她知道了
What's up with Yuhui?
小唐这是怎么了
Suddenly spouting
突然说一些奇奇怪怪
some crazy stuff.
有一搭没一搭的
No clue.
这谁知道啊
She's been like this for days,
这几天一直都这样
got a short fuse or something.
跟吃了火药似的
You don't think
她不会是
she found out about us, do you?
知道咱俩的事了吧
Did she rat us out to the boss?
她跟领导说了
If you're gonna freak out
看你这点心理素质
like this, we might
要是怕的话
as well break up now.
现在掰了算了
Break...
掰了
What?
什么掰了
Break what?
掰什么了
Mr Li.
李总
After all this time
咱们这个项目
we've put into this project,
谈了这么长时间了
can't just break it now, huh?
不能说掰就掰吧
Alright.
这样吧
Let's grab
下班
dinner after work.
一起吃个饭
Huh?
乖乖
You're just as weird as her.
你也奇奇怪怪地大早上
Chill out.
你先别担心了
She hasn't blown the whistle yet.
她不还没把事捅出去吗
And
而且
she's got
她不是
a thing for your husband, right?
对你们家纪总有意思
If she ruins
要是现在这事
everything now,
真捅得鱼死网破
Ji Yuheng ain't gonna be pleased.
纪昱恒能对她有好脸色
She's not that stupid.
我看她也不傻
But we can't risk it.
可是我们俩不敢赌啊
Especially him.
尤其是他
Nobody knows
别人不了解
him like I do.
我还不清楚吗
He's been through hell
他这半年过得
these past few months.
太不容易了
Now things are
好不容易各方面
finally picking up.
都有点起色
I can't let
我不希望
this mess ruin it
他因为这个事情
for him.
再受牵连
If she pulls this card
那如果她
and says you
真拿这事威胁你
gotta dump him,
让你们分手
you gonna cave?
你愿意吗
Of course not.
当然不行
Cool.
那不就得了
If you've
只要你俩
got each other's backs to
有共同战胜困难的决心
fight through it,
双向奔赴
nothing's gonna
这世上就没有什么坎
stop you.
是过不去的
True.
确实
I'm really touched by the
有被这种恋爱脑思路
lovestruck you.
治愈到
You know what.
我跟你说啊
If I knew
要是我知道
you were dying
你们这么想去
to see
见那个什么
Xia Mingrui,
夏明睿
I would've ambushed him
我昨晚就把他堵在
outside Jinlin Bar last night.
金霖轩门口了
You saw him last night?
你昨天晚上见到他了
Last night,
昨晚
my dad got drunk there,
我爸在金霖轩喝多了
so I went to pick him up.
我去接的他
Right at the entrance,
我当时在那个门口
I saw Mr Xia getting into
就看到他和那个
the same car with Geng Nianyi.
耿念一上了同一辆车
Something's fishy there.
这两人肯定有问题
Geng Nianyi?
耿念一
That lady?
是那个耿念一吗
Yeah.
就是啊
Isn't she married?
她不是结婚了吗
I heard she married some
不是传说她嫁了一个
secretive dude or whatever.
神秘男人什么的
Who says that secretive dude
你怎么知道那神秘男人
ain't Xia Mingrui?
就不是夏明睿
That place's a fancy joint,
金霖轩这种场合
without a connection, you can't
要不是有人接应
even make it to the parking lot.
连停车场都进不去
Just no one's
可能只是
snapped them together yet.
没有被拍到过而已
You sure?
你确定你没搞错啊
Anyway.
反正呢
They were all over
他们当时举止
each other,
特别地亲密
something's up if
如果不是夫妻
they're not hitched.
那更有问题
Weiyi.
惟依
Just got my paycheck,
我刚领到工资了
gonna hit the grocery
打算去附近的超市
store nearby.
买点东西
You coming?
你一起吗
Go.
去吧
He's got the night shift.
他晚上要值班
Gotta see him now
如果中午不见面
or it's tomorrow.
恐怕今天又见不着
Alright, alright.
好我知道了
Go then.
赶紧去吧
Enjoy your time with him.
省得你身在曹营心在汉
Yeah.
那是
Got the sweetest love
谁叫我现在拥有世界上
in the world.
最甜蜜美好的爱情呢
Eww.
真酸
Go.
赶紧走
Alright, I'm off.
行那我先走了
Two aroma diffusers.
香薰得拿俩
They'll
这个
gives the house a cozy vibe.
能够提升家庭的氛围
And a kettle.
水壶也得来呀
Gotta stay hydrated.
平时得多养养生
My hangers are happy colors
我家用的就是这种
like this,
多巴胺色系
lifting my mood.
看着让人心情就好
The color is the key, huh?
你选衣架看颜色是吧
Quality's good, trust me.
质量也很好的 好不好
Don't worry.
你放心
I won't splurge.
我现在心里绷着根弦呢
Just some necessities.
都买的是生活必需品
Okay.
行
You need this.
这种也得来
Hang your
一般衬衣啊
shirt with this.
得用这个晾才不会皱
Your cop uniforms
警察先生以后的衣服呢
gotta be clean and crisp,
一定是又干净又平整
no wrinkles or you'll
不然皱皱巴巴的
lose that tough cop vibe.
可没有威严
Got it.
拿了
Let's go.
走吧
Anything else?
还去买点什么呢
Right, laundry detergent.
洗衣液好像也没买
Mine at home smells great
我家的洗衣液特别好用
and lasts forever.
留香时间长还很清新
Gonna ask nanny
我赶紧问一下阿姨
what kind it is.
是什么牌子
Got it.
知道了
Let's go.
走吧
1,385 yuan
一共是
in total.
一千三百八十五元
How're you paying?
您怎么支付呢
Wait!
等会儿
Just these?
这么点东西
Over 1,300 yuan?
要一千三百多
We don't
这香薰
need the diffuser
还有这毛巾
or towels.
我不要了 退了吧
Okay.
好
Wait.
那个先别退
Keep them if you like.
惟依你喜欢话就留下
I got this on my credit card.
我刷信用卡就行
I've changed my mind.
我想了一下
I don't use
这两样东西
these often.
我确实也不太用得到
Just return them.
退了 退了
Alright, that's
好了 现在一共是
1,160 yuan now.
一千一百六十元
Your code?
我扫你
So expensive.
还要一千一百多
Here.
来
It's done.
好可以了
First time checking the receipt.
我第一次看购物小票
These laundry pods
原来这个洗衣凝珠
are pricey!
这么贵啊
No worries.
没事
They'll last me quite a while.
这些够用小半年
What? The chopsticks
还有这筷子
are 40 yuan
就这么几双
just for a few pairs?
为什么要四十块钱
Might as well
那我还不如用
use disposables.
外卖那一次性筷子呢
Never mind.
不重要
Chopsticks are greener.
这不是环保吗
Money really flies fast.
原来钱这么不经花
Didn't buy much,
感觉也没买什么呀
but ate up
可是你试用期
a third of your trial pay.
三分之一的工资就没了
Just
你买的呢
some basics.
都是生活必需品
I don't have many
况且我也没什么
other expenses.
花钱地方
No worries.
剩下的工资够用
I may still be
剩下的钱呢
able to save some money.
说不定还能攒一攒呢
My heart hurts.
我心疼
For what?
这有什么心疼的
I'm fine.
我没事
For the money.
心疼钱
So this is what it feels like.
原来心疼钱是这种感觉
Ms Geng.
耿小姐您好
Hope I'm not disturbing you...
很冒昧打扰您
Nah.
不行
She sees tons of people,
她每天见那么多人
probably forgot
说不定早就忘了
me already.
我是谁了
Ms Geng.
耿小姐您好
It's Tu Xiaoning
我是涂筱柠
from Dairui Bank.
代瑞银行的客户经理
Remember me from the expo?
我们在展销会上见过面
Hope I'm not disturbing you,
很冒昧打扰您
but if you're free today,
您今天方便的话
would it be possible to meet up?
我们可以见一面吗
See you there.
来这儿吧
Going out?
出去啊
Fanggang.
小赵哥
Punch me out, will ya?
帮我打个外勤
Got a client meeting.
我见客户
Okay.
好
Hi, Ms Geng.
耿小姐您好
Please have a seat.
坐
Thanks.
谢谢
Excuse me.
您好
May I take your order?
您喝点什么
I'm good.
不用了
Get her a banana milkshake, please.
给她来一杯香蕉牛奶吧
Okay.
好的
Thanks.
谢谢
That should be on me.
是我应该谢你才对
You didn't take
上次多出来的钱
the money last time.
你也没有收
Just came to say
其实我没有别的意思
thanks again,
我就是想真诚地
sincerely.
感谢你一下
I hate
我这个人啊
owing people favors.
不喜欢欠别人人情
So I'm here
我这次来呢
to say thank you
就是想再真诚地
again.
感谢你一下
Take it, please.
你一定要收下
Ms Geng.
耿小姐
I can't take it.
这钱我真的不能收
Then, what do you need?
那涂小姐你想要什么呢
Wouldn't have
如果你什么都不要
contacted me otherwise.
就不会主动约我了
Wait for me out there.
你先去外面等我吧
Okay.
好了
Now you can talk.
现在你可以说了
Ms Geng.
耿小姐
Please
我想
set up a meeting
麻烦您
between Ji Yuheng from Dairui
安排代瑞的纪昱恒
and Mr. Xia.
跟夏总见一面
Day 2 in Jinghai.
京海旅游第二天
Go check out Qingbei Uni
今天就去清北大学
and soak up some academic vibes.
沾染一下学霸的气息吧
Yuheng.
老纪
What are you up to?
你搞什么鬼呀
You got up early this morning,
你说你今天一大早起来
shampooed and primped
又是洗头又是捯饬自己
yourself
你搞得跟那
like a peacock.
开屏的孔雀似的
Got a crush
你是不是看上
on someone?
哪个妹子了
Nah.
别闹
You ready to give up the single life?
不想当孤家寡人啦
Hey.
同学
Wait!
等一下
Look out!
小心
Thanks.
谢谢
What did you
你刚刚
wanna say?
叫我有什么事吗
Nothing.
没什么
Wrong person.
认错人了
Let's go.
走吧
You okay?
没事吧
I was terrified.
吓死我了
I'm okay.
没事
What the hell?
怎么回事这
Who did it!?
谁那么缺德大白天的
Changes always beat plans.
计划总没变化快
Jinghai.
京海
See you!
下次见喽
What's up?
你咋了
Nothing.
没什么
Let's go.
走吧